<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C# on Kevin Du</title><link>https://kevindu.dev/tags/c%23/</link><description>Recent content in C# on Kevin Du</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kevindu.dev/tags/c%23/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Big Boat Battle</title><link>https://kevindu.dev/projects/ship-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevindu.dev/projects/ship-game/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../images/projects/ship_demo_gif.gif" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This my top-down combat game where you pilot a toy boat against waves of enemy ships within a foggy pool! Some interesting features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volumetric Fog&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be parted by objects which attenuate the fog density&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Procedural Water&lt;/strong&gt; with Ripples using render textures and a wave shader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Render texture scrolling to follow the player across a potentially infinite map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boid NPC behaviors to create enemy ship formations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procedural behavior generation for enemies, with possible states depending on assigned tasks and enemy type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Procedural enemies&lt;/strong&gt;, with varying coloration, decoration, and armaments based on enemy types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A variety of ships procedurally modelled in Houdini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
 &lt;thead&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;th style="text-align: center"&gt;&lt;img src="../../images/projects/ship_closeup_crop.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
 &lt;th style="text-align: center"&gt;&lt;img src="../../images/projects/boat_houdini.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/thead&gt;
 &lt;tbody&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td style="text-align: center"&gt;In-game prototyping&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td style="text-align: center"&gt;Houdini modelling&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demo Video: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cPxqBuK4olA"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cPxqBuK4olA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Catanks</title><link>https://kevindu.dev/projects/catanks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevindu.dev/projects/catanks/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3793790/Catanks/"&gt;Catanks&lt;/a&gt; is UPGRADE’s 2024–2025 semester project, released on &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3793790/Catanks/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as a top-down arcade tank shooter where you battle the numerous NPC rat tanks. As &lt;strong&gt;producer&lt;/strong&gt; and one of 2 lead developers, I worked closely with 10+ programmers and coordinated the game’s asset and production pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was responsible for most of the &lt;strong&gt;core game design planning and game mechanics programming&lt;/strong&gt; during the first half of development, before shifting my focus to developing the Classic Mode inspired by Wii Tanks during the second half. This included implementing advanced &lt;strong&gt;enemy AI&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;pathfinding systems&lt;/strong&gt; using state machines and &lt;strong&gt;bullet-dodging behaviors&lt;/strong&gt; to give the players a meaningful challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mechanika</title><link>https://kevindu.dev/projects/mechanika/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevindu.dev/projects/mechanika/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../images/projects/mechanika_gameplay1.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 2D rhythm-oriented bullet hell was my first Unity game, and I was one of two programmers in a group of five people. Although the game may have been a bit overscoped, being an amalgamation of the ideas of all 5 of us, I am pretty satisfied with how the game turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was responsible for game design and map layouts, and I implemented the NPC enemies, including the two super-difficult rhythm-oriented bosses. It was here where I&amp;rsquo;d say I fell in love with game design and ignited my passion for programming NPC behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VR Cricothyrotomy Simulator</title><link>https://kevindu.dev/projects/cricothyrotomy-sim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevindu.dev/projects/cricothyrotomy-sim/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of Penn Medicine through the PURM summer research internship, I developed a VR surgical airway trainer in Unity for Unity for Meta Quest 2, 3, and Pro headsets. A cricothyrotomy is a critical emergency airway procedure performed when conventional methods fail. Due to the rarity of such cases, hands-on experience is extremely limited. This VR simulator module addresses this issue, with the aim of being used alongside conventional medical education by improving procedural familiarity in a safe, repeatable environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>