<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GLSL on Kevin Du</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/glsl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GLSL on Kevin Du</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/glsl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mini Minecraft</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/mini-minecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/mini-minecraft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/projects/minecraft_landscape.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My team and I built a 3D game engine inspired by Minecraft, using C++ and GLSL. This experience taught me a lot about GPU rendering pipelines. My contributions include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Procedural biome assets&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Procedural biome grass coloring&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water waves and specular reflection&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Post-process camera overlay for water and lava&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Distance fog&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Player physics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Procedural cave generation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;procedural-assets&#34;&gt;Procedural Assets&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I created 3 procedural assets: normal trees, pine trees, and ice spikes. Their sizes and appearances sample their y-positions as an efficient way to obtain randomness. They are placed along the x-z-plane based on simple noise, with their numbers limited per chunk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo Path Tracer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/pathtracer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/pathtracer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Monte Carlo path tracer is implemented in GLSL, with the majority of computation performed on the GPU. The renderer draws on concepts from &lt;em&gt;Physically Based Rendering&lt;/em&gt; and casts rays per fragment from the camera through each pixel, simulating multiple light bounces. At each bounce, direct light sampling is weighted and contributes to the overall radiance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The path tracer implements image-based environment lighting for global illumination, different types of lights and materials/BDSFs, and uses multiple importance sampling to improve convergence speed and reduce noise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
